Celebrate the legend
Sparkle is a music, drama, romance film directed by Salim Akil.
Musical prodigy, Sparkle struggles to become a star while
overcoming issues that are tearing her family apart.
From an affluent Detroit area and daughter to a single mother, she tries to balance a new romance with music manager Stix while dealing with the
unexpected challenges her new life will bring as she and her two sisters strive to become a dynamic singing group during the Motown-era.
Sparkle, played by Jordin Sparks.
Emma, played by Whitney Houston.
Stix, played by Derek Luke.
Satin, played by Mike Epps.
Sister, played by Carmen Ejogo.
Delores, played by Tika Sumpter.
Sparkle is a 2012 American musical film directed by
Salim Akil and produced by Stage 6 Films.
It was released on August 17, 2012, by TriStar Pictures.
Inspired by The Supremes, Sparkle is a remake of the 1976 film of the same title, which
centered on three singing teenage sisters who form a girl group in the late 1950s.
The remake takes place in Detroit, Michigan, in 1968 during the Motown era.
The film stars Jordin Sparks in her film debut, Whitney Houston, Derek Luke, Cee Lo Green,
Mike Epps, Carmen Ejogo, Tika Sumpter, Tamela Mann, and Omari Hardwick.
Sparkle features songs from the original film written by soul musician
Curtis Mayfield as well as new compositions by R&B artist R.
This film is the debut of R&B/pop singer and American
Idol winner Jordin Sparks as an actress.
Sparkle also marks Houston's final feature film role before her death
on February 11, 2012, three months after filming ended.
The film is dedicated to her memory.
The film explores themes of new york city, motown,
duringcreditsstinger, girl group, rise to fame.
The tone is emotional.